welcome to edit ating with genre baekje
we live stream every weekday morning at
9:30 a.m. Eastern Time with Monday's
alternating between a new lesson Dharma
day and a review of the whole ecology
practices of hiya day for previous
lessons and sets I'll see the
description if you're joining us for the
first time please continue
meeting with us but I strongly suggest
you go immediately to the first lesson
watch it
start practicing and then every Saturday
or Sunday or whatever day of the week
you happen not free do another lesson
and then you'll quickly integrate up
with this I would ask everybody to
please like this video stream to
increase its its its visibility on the
YouTube algorithm and many of you have
been helping me do that and I appreciate
it
how did you just keep doing it because
we're trying to reach as many people as
we possibly can at the end of every set
we have QA and please limit the
questions to that QA two questions
around the course that we've been on
this whole ecology of practices for more
encompassing questions please join us on
our large screen Q&A on YouTube at 3
p.m. Eastern Time every third Friday of
the month and that will be July 17th of
this month believe that's everything in
terms of announcements and so what we'll
do today is we'll sit and then we we
have our techno mage back with us today
Omar and so we will try to do a little
bit longer or some extra questions at
the end to try and catch up with that
all right so everybody please get in
position set your phones on do not
disturb and we will begin together when
I say begin
begin
[Music]
slowly come out of you practice trying
as best you can to integrate with you
cultivated in you practice with your
everyday consciousness cognition
character and communitas perhaps by
reciting the five promises to yourself
okay so I have some time for some
questions so the first one is took on
Soho to see you again five promises
there's various versions of them so I'll
do the version that I'm using right now
it's a little bit different than what I
taught people initially with the fire
promises so I taught a more basic
version but it can grow the version I
use goes I'll go through the five
promises with reverence and respect I
promise not to misuse or abused life but
to treat life wisely or sometimes people
say mindfully or carefully or lovingly I
say wisely but choose the one that
resonates most with you I really gets
you engaged and so to go back with
reverence in this respect I promise not
to misuse or views life but to treat
life wisely some people also say to
practice enhancing and enriching life
again there's you have to get a
constellation of words in your mantra
that resonate almost like Alexio Davina
for you so although I'm giving you what
I'll use I don't want you to think that
that's some sort of exclusive
requirement so with reverence and
respect I promise not to misuse or views
life but to treat life wisely
remembering the being mode in the
aspiration towards a Lisbon wisdom and
enlightenment and then with reverence
and respect I promise not to misuse or
views material objects but to treat them
wisely
remembering the being mode in the
aspiration to wizard them and
enlightenment
with reverence and respect I promise not
to misuse or abuse speech but two
speakers to speak wisely
remembering the being mode and the
aspiration to wisdom and enlightenment
with reverence and respect I promise not
to misuse or abuse my sexuality but to
practice it wisely
remembering the being mode in the
aspiration towards wisdom and
enlightenment with resident reverence
and respect the promise not to misuse or
views altered states of consciousness
but to use them wisely
remembering the being mode in the
aspiration to wisdom and enlightenment
and when I'm doing each one I try to
Center my attention on the sense of life
in me for the first one the sense of the
material objects around me my speech
Center a sexual center my consciousness
as I'm making the promises one more time
I'm giving you the basic idea that you
need you need to craft this in a way
that resonates with you that most it's
you to participate in the intention and
the aspiration for transformation own
and fulvic when doing the five factors
particularly I thought you need to go
through all five factors I find
sometimes the thought goes away or I can
get a new distraction when I start to
apply the five factors so it can
sometimes feel like I'm seeking out my
initial thought distraction order to
apply all five five factors is excellent
question by which point it can seem to
make more sense to return to my breath
instead you're exactly right Barnes it's
exactly right so if when you're when
you're starting to do the five factors
the thought goes away that's it you just
return so the principles are it goes
away we do return to your breath if you
go to way if you're distracted from your
distraction you return to your breath if
neither one of you go away but it's
getting to be such an intense struggle
that all your you are doing is enduring
and not learning then you return to the
breath so the question the answer to
your question is yes exactly and
your sense of this was exactly bang on
so that's growth Gabriel Rubinstein hi
Gabriel and then I'm very rarely getting
any real insights about the person just
a general sense of reciprocal opening
being and generic empathy awareness that
they have a subjective experience any
suggestions to get more realization of
what what is not yet seen thanks in
advance so Gabriel I would recommend
doing that what you're getting is quite
good on that sense of reciprocal opening
being a general sympathy that sense of
empathy I would concentrate before
trying to deepen it in your practice try
to practice it throughout your day when
you're encountering people when you're
encountering situations or when you're
encountering uncomfortable emotions in
yourself if you can get throughout your
day that would that that becomes more
second nature to you that reciprocal
opening the vnode generic empathy once
that's working and once that's really
sort of taken root and living then you
can turn back to the meta and look for
something deeper and what you can start
to do is to try to get a sense of right
how you might be projecting onto that
person so they're the optimal person for
that or the optimal situation are
situations that are really pushing
buttons or people that really push your
buttons and try to get a sense of that
about you which you're not seeing
precisely because you're projecting on
them please remember what I said though
it's very important to first practice
this Metta that that reciprocal opening
that general empathy that general
connectedness throughout your day that
has to really have taken deep root
because only then can you try within
Metta to especially with the conflict
person or the conflict situation or o or
your own emotions that you run away from
or you don't know you don't like or you
dis identify with then you can see you
can do Metta towards them and try and
get a sense of what's being projected
for those of you who are a union this is
a kind of shadow work what you're trying
to do is realize not only the right the
unconscious ident
vacation which were doing in regular
meta but the deeper aspects of this
which is the not more than just the
unconscious the the in the sense of
being automatic and habitual and you've
got to work on that first I'm going to
keep saying you have to work on that
first but once that starts to really
loosen up and open up then you start to
get the apertures for which you can
start to see that those aspects of the
process of identification that are being
repressed or dis identified held away
from and therefore often projective onto
other people but please it's very
important that that order that I gave
you is followed algernon Themis hallo
Algernon
which of the five promises would most
include the idea of honoring and being
grateful for the gift of one's physical
body so that's an interesting one I
thought about that that's a very good
one
so for me I tends to be the the life so
we're not what I promised not to abuse
or misuse right life I feel the life
within myself but it's not my life I'm
feeling life as the participatory locus
that connects me to all living things
I'll see I don't just refer to or think
about living things I participate in
being alive I instantiate the property
of life that's in other things so I go
into I sort of when I'm making that
promise I'm not that's what I memorize
the locus is in me but it's not about me
it's the way it's the place from which I
am making the connection but I know
there's people who also do that you make
the promise to include their body when
they're doing it towards not misusing or
abusing material things because the body
of course is the material thing and that
that makes perfect sense to me - for me
the the life aspect seems to be more
resonant I suppose and I haven't
explored this personally so this is a
conjecture on my part or supposition I
should say on my part I suppose that you
could do both you could have sort of the
sense of you know your your body as a
living entity to give you that
participatory connect
two living things when you're making the
promise towards life but you could also
get the sense of your body as a spatial
material physical thing when you're
making the promise towards material
things actually I think I'm going to try
that but that would be my my answer to
you Sam Lambert I'm currently working
through the early first video should
avoid the live streams altogether until
I've caught up would like to partake it
can some live six before they finished
Sam please sit with us right from the
beginning like as long as you're working
your way regularly and reliable through
the previous lessons you you you will
you don't think this is too preposterous
or pretentious that you belong here
you do you belong here it you do
everybody is right and even when
everybody's done the lessons it is
always the case that we are all at
different places and moving at a
different pace so as long as you are
regularly and reliably making way
through the lessons please join us every
day if you possibly can
you're most welcome and you belong here
then then go hello Ben good to hear from
you again a while back I experienced
what I think is a flow state of love and
dynamic love and interaction with my
kids but that passed soon and now I have
only glimpses of that mental state and
meditation helped me to retrieve and
large and embody that mental state gif
so how are you directing meta at it
exactly how okay so Ben I want to
recommend a book to you by by a slender
limb called trying not to trot trying
not to try because it the more you what
you can do is set up the conditions but
you always thought it's like like sort
of you know setting up the conditions
for a fire but the spark has to take up
of its own so mindfulness and chicks my
art is this and there's evidence for
this increasingly mindfulness practice
is especially evident both Metta and the
past 'no mindfulness practices and doing
the moving practices these are all
predictive of an enhanced likelihood of
getting into the flow state but it's not
a direct algorithmic process you can't
do this and then that will just
immediately cause the event of
what you're doing is increasing your
overall receptivity you also have to pay
attention to the external circumstances
in which the flow state might take place
you have to make sure that there's very
clear and unambiguous information
between you and the situation you have
to make sure that your actions and the
responses from whatever it is in the
environment perhaps your kids or
something else or someone else or
something else it's very tightly coupled
so that when you do something the
environment responds in a tightly
coupled fashion so clarity coupled and
then error not has to matter it's right
if you make a mistake it will disrupt
the interaction so you what does that
mean you have to really challenge your
skills your skills have to be challenged
continuously so definitely the
mindfulness practice that will bring it
back in the sense of making you more
receptive to it taking on a life of its
own I should recommend reading the
slingerland book trying not to try and
then you can take a look at the
conditions in the environment that will
actually be most conducive to flow
Kareema hello Karima what is the
cognitive reason in Praja
people choose which way to inhale and
inhale I'm still trying and liking both
ways I don't know dream on I don't know
I haven't been able to come up with a
good hypothesis for that I do know it's
a reliable feature I mean I think one of
it is is its people when some people
like the inhale they're feeling their
abdomen expanding and I think they're
paying more attention to the breath as
the spatial expansion of the abdomen
where other people they're paying more
attention to the direction in which the
breath is moving so for the inhale if
you're paying attention to the abdomen
right you're feeling that but if you're
paying attention to the sensation of the
air coming in you want to be doing the
passionate rather than the meta eye but
the cognitive reason is other than
what's the more likely focus I don't
know I don't know what it reflects about
people's cognitive styles or
personalities or anything like that but
I there that's it I'm sorry like I said
I think it's there's a people are
focused differently on how they're
tracking their breath but what that
difference points to behind it I don't
know I really don't know in Praja no
matter you are not blessing just
expanding it into connecting yes Grima
that's exactly right
that's exactly right this is where
giving priority to the existential
interpretation of meta over the merely
emotional interpretation of meta comes
into prominence because that more
existential interpretation is taken up
into Praja so that's exactly correct
so everyone thank you very much for
joining it looks like we're all caught
up now on our questions which is great I
want I'm very happy and glad that my
good friend and techno major Maura is
back and then he was today here today
making everything flow so fluidly and
fluently and of course thank you as
always for Jason he pinched it yesterday
pinch hit it yesterday and and he's
always here today making sure that chaos
has held that bay he's kind of like a
paladin fighting the Dragons of chaos
please subscribe to this channel to be
notified of the next video you will also
find links to the lecture series
awakening for the meaning crisis and the
dialogo series voices with Rob a key
where these themes are explored in depth
and situated within a broader and
compasses life invite others who might
benefit by sharing this series there's a
lot of people I've done a couple of
workshops for other channels like future
thinkers so there's more and more people
that are getting interested in this
ecology practices and finding it
beneficial and helpful so everybody
please keep doing that it has been
it's been very successful and it's been
very helpful
pretty sure Brett is here pleasure of
doubt please join the discord server to
chat with others there's a link in the
description and that this chord server
you're gonna I'm on there every couple
of weeks all the people that are on
birth voices live a key eventually end
up on there doing excellent Q&A there's
all kinds of work being done on around
the video series and and it's taken on a
life of its own and it's growing
powerfully and it's I'm just it's I just
want to say for a moment you know
there's times when you realize that
things are sort of you know you've had
some success you know like I got tenure
things like that and that's important
but when I realized that like with the
people in the discord server that it's
very much a community now that's taken
on a life of its own and it's like it's
like it's like it's like it's like the
kite so I don't think it's the wrong way
there's like the kind of success when
you've had a child and you see the child
coming into you know autonomy it's truly
it's truly wonderful please remember
that we are doing this every weekday
morning at 9:30 Eastern Time and please
remember that continuity of practice is
more important than sheer quantity of
practice there is no enemy worse than
your own mind and body
no friend no Ally no true companion on
the path better than your own mind and
my body be lamps unto yourselves and to
each other
take good care everyone I'll see you on
Monday it's Donna day